'use strict';

const questions = [
    {
        question: '1. While being the oldest National Park in North America, what year was Yellowstone designated?',
        ansA: '1776',
        ansB: '1801',
        ansC: '1872',
        ansD: '1972',
        correct: '1872'
    },
    {
        question: '2. What are examples of geothermal features?',
        ansA: 'hot springs and geysers',
        ansB: 'mountains and canyons',
        ansC: 'trees and rivers',
        ansD: 'climate change',
        correct: 'hot springs and geysers'
    },
    {
        question: '3. Approximately, what percentage of the World’s geysers are in Yellowstone?',
        ansA: '5%',
        ansB: '25%',
        ansC: '50%',
        ansD: '75%',
        correct: '75%'
    },
    {
        question: '4. Approximatley, how long ago did Yellowstone last erupted?',
        ansA: '1,500 years ago',
        ansB: '425,000 years ago',
        ansC: '640,000 years ago',
        ansD: '1 million years ago',
        correct: '640,000 years ago'
    },
    {
        question: '5. Which U.S. states does Yellowstone National Park spread across?',
        ansA: 'Maine, Canada, and New York',
        ansB: 'Idaho, Wyoming, and Montana',
        ansC: 'California, Nevada, and Arizona',
        ansD: 'Colorado, New Mexico, and Utah',
        correct: 'Idaho, Wyoming, and Montana'
    },
    {
        question: '6. While being the largest high elevation lake in North America, what is the elevation of Yellowstone Lake?',
        ansA: '1254 feet',
        ansB: '5280 feet',
        ansC: '7733 feet',
        ansD: '1 mile',
        correct: '7733 feet'
    },
    {
        question: '7. Which animal species in Yellowstone did the U.S. government eradicate, and then reintroduce to the ecosystem?',
        ansA: 'Bison',
        ansB: 'Grey Wolf',
        ansC: 'Moose',
        ansD: 'Dodo',
        correct: 'Grey Wolf'
    },
    {
        question: '8. Approximately, how many earthquakes does Yellowstone experience on a yearly basis?',
        ansA: 'Less than 10',
        ansB: '100',
        ansC: '500',
        ansD: 'more than a thousand',
        correct: 'more than a thousand'
    },
    {
        question: '9. Yellowstone is home to America’s largest and oldest natural herd of what type of animal? ',
        ansA: 'Bison',
        ansB: 'Grey Wolf',
        ansC: 'Grizzly Bear',
        ansD: 'Snow Leopards',
        correct: 'Bison'
    },
    {
        question: '10. How many current Native American tribes have a historic connection to the land and resources found in Yellowstone?',
        ansA: '1 tribe',
        ansB: '7 tribes',
        ansC: '16 tribes',
        ansD: '26 tribes',
        correct: '26 tribes'
    }
]